Alvin Charity

410-707-0539 | al.charity@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Thoughtful, detail-oriented polymath - I am a talented professional and I am excited to bring my extensive knowledge to a new environment. I have over twenty years of general writing experience, crafting precise copy for web pages, mobile apps, technical documentation, and training manuals. As a writer I have developed my skill by tackling challenges head-on, managing multiple projects with tight deadlines and complex subject matter. Along the way I have grown as a writer by being flexible enough to adapt to just about any writing style and tone, prioritizing clarity, accuracy, and collaboration in every word I write. I strongly believe that communicating across a diverse range of experiences and personalities can truly help people understand and learn from each other.

EXPERIENCE

Reflect.run July 2022 – Present

Contract Technical Writer

Project-based articles about web technologies and tools aimed at developers

- Research aspects of the developer workflow and tools
- Develop and execute small programming projects using TypeScript and JavaScript
- Write 1500+ word articles using the Markdown markup language

Draft.dev March 2022 – Present

Contract Technical Writer

Writing articles on an array of technical topics, including product documentation, scripts for the Python programming language, Web Scraping, and Data manipulation.

- Research topics on various web development and programming practices
- Create 1500+ word articles following an in-house style guide
- Collaborate with editors and subject matter experts for revisions and improvements to article content

Copper Banking

May 2022 — August 2022

Contract Copywriter

Creating copy for the web, mobile applications, SMS notifications, and printed material

- Work with members of the marketing team to develop content strategy for web and mobile applications
- Create copy to match the brand tone and voice, for teens and their parents
- Write space-constrained product feature descriptions from content briefs
- Draft messaging for SMS and in-app notifications to match the needs of marketing campaigns
- Revise printed material for focused and timely communication during in-person workshops

FullPath Transit

January 2021 – January 2022

Technical Writer / JavaScript Developer

Maintaining and documenting a JavaScript-based public transit tool used by communities in rural Oregon

- Review the codebase for consistency and bugs, reporting any found to lead developer
- Create new tools based on current codebase to provide additional functionality to users
- Document the API by listing all functions and parameters and creating flow diagrams
- Create a glossary of terms used by the tool to help guide new users

MOM's Organic Market

August 2012 - October 2020

Special Projects Lead

Create user guides and manuals for the company intranet; build, document, and maintain JavaScript based business automations

- Collaborate with Training and Communications team members to create intranet content, corporate policies, and standard operating procedures.
- Develop and implement a document schema for various guides, tools, and documents used by employees
- Create JavaScript automations for internal processes, such as employee time off requests, reimbursement requests, and employee management workflows
- Provide technical assistance to data specialists across departments to help improve product management

EDUCATION

Howard Community College Associate of Arts, English

May 2012

University of Maryland, Baltimore County

Earned 20 credits toward a Bachelor's degree in English

September 2012 — September 2014